You will understand nothing with my type of English.
لن تفهموا شيئا من الطريقة التي سأتحدث فيها الإنجليزية
It's good for you because you can have a break after all these fantastic people.
هذا أفضل بالنسبة لكم، لانه يمكنكم أخذ فترة راحة بعد كل هؤلاء الناس الرائعين.
I must tell you I am like that, not very comfortable,
لابد أن أقول لكم إنني لست مرتاح، شئ من هذا القبيل
because usually, in life, I think my job is absolutely useless.
لأني في العاده، أعتقد أن وظيفتي غير مهمة في الحياة على الإطلاق
I mean, I feel useless.
ما أقصد قوله هو أنني أشعر بأني عديم الفائده
Now after Carolyn, and all the other guys, I feel like shit.
الأن بعد كارولين، وجميع الأشخاص الباقين، أشعر بأني بلا قيمة
And definitively, I don't know why I am here,
وبالتأكيد، لا أعرف لماذا أنا هنا
but -- you know the nightmare you can have, like you are an impostor,
لكن -- هل تعرفوا الكوابيس التي تأتيكم، تحس فيها بأنك محتال
you arrive at the opera, and they push you, "You must sing!"
بعد وصولك إلى الأوبرا، يقوموا بدفعك، "يجب أن تغني!"
I don't know. (Laughter)
لا أعرف.
So, so, because I have nothing to show, nothing to say,
حسنا، حسنا، بما أنه ليس لدي شئ لأعرضه، أو لأقوله.
we shall try to speak about something else.
سنحاول التحدث في شئ اخر.
We can start, if you want, by understanding --
نستطيع البدء، إذا أردتم، من خلال الفهم --
it's just to start, it's not interesting, but -- how I work.
فقط لمجرد أن نبدأ، إنها ليست مثيرة للاهتمام لكن -- كيف أعمل.
When somebody comes to me and ask for what I am known,
عندما يأتي شخص لي ويسألني بماذا أشتهر.
I mean, yes, lemon squeezer, toilet brush, toothpick, beautiful toilet seats,
الذي أعنيه، نعم، عصارة الليمون، فرشاة المرحاض، عود الأسنان، مقاعد المرحاض الجميلة
and why not -- a toothbrush?
ولم لا -- فرشاة أسنان.
I don't try to design the toothbrush.
أنا لا أحاول تصميم فرشاة الأسنان.
I don't try to say, "Oh, that will be a beautiful object," or something like that.
أنا لا أحاول القول، "حسنا، هذا سيكون شئ جميل،" أو شئ من هذا القبيل.
That doesn't interest me.
هذا لا يثير اهتمامي.
Because there is different types of design.
لأن هنالك أنواع مختلفة من التصاميم.
The one, we can call it the cynical design,
نوع يمكننا أن نطلق عليه اسم التصميم الباعث إلى السخرية.
that means the design invented by Raymond Loewy in the '50s,
هذا يعني أن التصميم تم اختراعه بواسطة رايموند لووي في الخمسينات.
who said, what is ugly is a bad sale, la laideur se vend mal, which is terrible.
من قال، ما هو قبيح سيئ للبيع، القبح لا يباع، وهو أمر فظيع.
It means the design must be just the weapon for marketing,
هذا يعني أن التصميم يجب أن يكون مجرد سلاح للتسويق.
for producer to make product more sexy, like that,
للمنتجين كمثال، لجعل المنتج أكثر إثارة، شئ من هذا القبيل.
they sell more: it's shit, it's obsolete, it's ridiculous.
إنهم يبيعون أكثر، إنه مقرف، إنه باطل، إنه أمر سخيف.
I call that the cynical design.
أدعوا هذا التصميم الباعث إلى السخرية.
After, there is the narcissistic design:
بعد هذا، هناك التصميم المغرور أو المعجب بذاته.
it's a fantastic designer who designs only for other fantastic designers. (Laughter)
إنه المصمم الرائع الذي يصمم فقط لمصممين رائعين.
After, there is people like me, who try to deserve to exist,
بعد هذا، هناك أشخاص مثلي، الذين يحاولون أن يستحقوا الوجود.
and who are so ashamed to make this useless job, who try to do it in another way,
والذين يخجلون من العمل في وظيفة غير مفيدة، الذين يحاولون القيام بذلك بطريقة مختلفة.
and they try, I try, to not make the object for the object but for the result,
ويحاولون، وأنا أحاول، لعدم جعل الغاية من التصميم لذاته، ولكن الغاية من التصميم النتيجة،
for the profit for the human being, the person who will use it.
من أجل تحقيق فائدة للإنسان، وهو الشخص الذي سيستخدمه.
If we take the toothbrush -- I don't think about the toothbrush.
إذا أخذنا فرشاة الأسنان على سبيل المثال -- أنا لا أفكر في فرشاة الأسنان.
I think, "What will be the effect of the brush in the mouth?"
بل أفكر في، "ما تأثير الفرشاة في الفم؟"
And to understand what will be the effect of the toothbrush in the mouth,
ولفهم ماذا سيكون تأثير فرشاة الأسنان في الفم،
I must imagine: Who owns this mouth?
لابد أن أتخيل: من يملك هذا الفم؟
What is the life of the owner of this mouth? In what society [does] this guy live?
ما هي حياة مالك هذا الفم؟ في أي مجتمع يعيش؟
What civilization creates this society?
ماهي الحضارة التي أوجدت هذا المجتمع؟
What animal species creates this civilization?
ماهي فصائل الحيوانات التي ساهمت في وجود هذه الحضارة؟
When I arrive -- and I take one minute, I am not so intelligent --
عندما أصل -- وأستغرق دقيقة واحدة، أنا لست في غاية الذكاء --
when I arrive at the level of animal species, that becomes real interesting.
عند وصولي لمستوى فصائل الحيوانات، عندها يصبح مثيرا للإهتمام.
Me, I have strictly no power to change anything.
أنا، لا أملك أي قوة على الإطلاق لتغير أي شئ.
But when I come back, I can understand why I shall not do it,
ولكن عندما أعود، أستطيع فهم لماذا لا يجب أن أفعل ذلك.
because today to not do it, it's more positive than do it, or how I shall do it.
لأنه اليوم، أن لا تفعل ذلك هو أكثر إيجابية من فعله، أو كيف أفعل ذلك.
But to come back, where I am at the animal species, there is things to see.
ولكن دعونا نعود، عندما كنت أتحدث عن فصائل الحيوانات، هناك أشياء لنراها.
There is things to see, there is the big challenge.
هناك أشياء لنراها، يوجد تحد كبير.
The big challenge in front of us.
التحد الكبير أمامنا.
Because there is not a human production
لأنه لا يوجد إنتاج للإنسان.
which exists outside of what I call "the big image."
الذي يوجد خارج ما أسميه "الصورة الكبيرة."
The big image is our story, our poetry, our romanticism.
الصورة الكبيرة هي عبارة عن قصصنا، أشعارنا، عاطفتنا.
Our poetry is our mutation, our life.
الشعر لدينا هو طفرة، وهو حياتنا.
We must remember, and we can see that in any book of my son of 10 years old,
عندما نتذكر، إذا أخذنا أي كتاب من كتب ابني الذي يبلغ 10 سنوات، نستطيع أن نرى
that life appears four billion years ago, around -- four billion point two?
يبدو أن الحياة ظهرت قبل أربعة بلايين سنة، حوالي -- أربعة بلايين ومئتين مليون؟
Voice offstage: Four point five.
صوت الكواليس، أربعة وخمسمائة.
Yes, point five, OK, OK, OK! (Laughter) I'm a designer,
نعم، وخمسمائة، حسنا، حسنا، حسنا! أنا مجرد مصمم.
that's all, of Christmas gifts.
هذا كل شئ، من هدايا الكريسماس.
And before, there was this soup, called "soupe primordiale,"
وقبل ذلك كان هناك هذا الحساء، ويدعى "حساء برايمورديال."
this first soup -- bloop bloop bloop --
أول حساء -- بلوب بلوب بلوب --
sort of dirty mud, no life, nothing.
نوع من الطين القذر، لا حياة، لا شئ.
So then -- pshoo-shoo -- lightning -- pshoo -- arrive --
بعد هذا -- صوت برق -- ضوء -- وصول --
pshoo-shoo -- makes life -- bloop bloop -- and that dies.
فسو-شو -- يجعل الحياة -- بلوب بلوب -- ويموت.
Some million years after -- pshoo-shoo, bloop-bloop -- ah, wake up!
بعد ملايين السنين -- فسو شو، بلوب بلوب -- اه، لقد استيقظ!
At the end, finally, that succeeds, and life appears.
وفي النهاية، وأخيرا، ينجح ذلك، وتظهر الحياة.
We was so, so stupid. The most stupid bacteria.
كنا في غاية الغباء، أغبى بكتيريا على الإطلاق.
Even, I think, we copy our way to reproduce, you know what I mean,
أيضا أعتقد، أننا قمنا بنسخ الطريقة التي ننتج بها، تعرفون ماذا أقصد.
and something of -- oh no, forget it.
وشئ من -- أوه لا، انسوا ذلك.
After, we become a fish; after, we become a frog;
وبعد ذلك نصبح سمكه; وبعدها فإننا نصبح ضفدع;
after, we become a monkey; after, we become what we are today: a super-monkey,
وبعد ذلك نصبح قرد; وبعدها فإننا نصبح ما نحن عليه اليوم: قرد خارق.
and the fun is, the super-monkey we are today, is at half of the story.
والممتع في الأمر، أن القرد الخارق الذي نحن عليه اليوم، هو نصف القصة.
Can you imagine? From that stupid bacteria to us,
هل يمكنكم أن تتخيلوا؟ انتقلنا من البكتيريا الغبيه إلى ما نحن عليه.
with a microphone, with a computer, with an iPod: four billion years.
مع المايكروفون، مع الكمبيوتر، مع أجهزة اي بود -- أربعة مليارات سنة.
And we know, and especially Carolyn knows, that when the sun will implode,
وكلنا نعرف، وخاصة كارولين، أنه عندما سوف تنهار الشمس،
the earth will burn, explode, I don't know what,
سوف تحترق الأرض، تنفجر، وما إلى ذلك،
and this is scheduled for four, four billion years?
وهذا مقرر بعد أربعة، أربعة مليارات سنة؟
Yes, she said, something like that. OK, that means we are at half of the story.
قالت نعم، شئ من هذا القبيل. حسنا، هذا يعني أننا في نصف القصة.
Fantastic! It's a beauty!
رائع! في غاية الجمال!
Can you imagine? It's very symbolic.
هل يمكنكم أن تتصورا؟ إنه شئ رمزي جدا.
Because the bacteria we was had no idea of what we are today.
لأن البكتيريا التي كنا عليها، ليس لديها أدنى فكرة عما نحن عليه اليوم.
And today, we have no idea of what we shall be in four billion years.
واليوم، ليس لدينا أدنى فكرة عما سنصبح عليه بعد أربعة مليارات سنة.
And this territory is fantastic.
وهذا المجال في غاية الروعة.
That is our poetry. That is our beautiful story.
هذا هو شعرنا ، هذه قصتنا الجميلة.
It's our romanticism. Mu-ta-tion. We are mutants.
إنها عاطفتنا، الطفرات. نحن مسوخ.
And if we don't deeply understand, if we don't integrate that we are mutants,
وإذا كنا لا نفهم بعمق، وإذا لم نقم بدمج فكرة أننا مسوخ،
we completely miss the story.
فسوف نفقد القصة تماما.
Because every generation thinks we are the final one.
لأن كل جيل يرى أنه اخر جيل.
We have a way to look at Earth like that, you know,
كما تعلمون، لدينا طريقة للنظر إلى الأرض بهذا الشكل.
"I am the man. The final man.
أنا الإنسان، اخر إنسان.
You know, we mutate during four billion years before, but now, because it's me, we stop. Fin. (Laughter)
كما تعلمون، نحن تحورنا خلال الأربعة مليارات سنة السابقة، ولكن الأن، لأنه لي فقد توقفنا.
For the end, for the eternity, it is one with a red jacket."
من أجل النهاية، من أجل الخلود، إنه شخص مع سترة حمراء."
Something like that. I am not sure of that. (Laughter)
شئ من هذا القبيل، أنا لست متأكدا من ذلك.
Because that is our intelligence of mutation and things like that.
لأن هذا هو مجال ذكائنا في الطفرات وشئ من هذا القبيل.
There is so many things to do; it's so fresh.
هناك العديد من الأمور للقيام بها، أمور جديدة كليا.
And here is something: nobody is obliged to be a genius,
على سبيل المثال: لا أحد ملزم أن يكون عبقريا.
but everybody is obliged to participate.
لكن الجميع ملزم بالمشاركة.
And to participate, for a mutant, there is a minimum of exercise, a minimum of sport.
وللمشاركة كمسخ أو متحول، هناك حد أدنى من التمارين، حد أدنى من الرياضة.
We can say that.
نستطيع قول ذلك.
The first, if you want -- there is so many --
في البداية، إذا كنتم تريدون -- هناك الكثير -
but one which is very easy to do, is the duty of vision.
لكن من أبسط الأمور للقيام به، هو واجب الرؤية.
I can explain you. I shall try.
أستطيع أن أشرح لكم. سأحاول.
If you walk like that, it's OK, it's OK, you can walk,
إذا كنت تمشي هكذا، لا بأس، لا بأس، يمكنك المشي.
but perhaps, because you walk with the eyes like that, you will not see, oh, there is a hole.
ولكن ربما، لأنك تمشي وعيناك هكذا، لن تستطيع الرؤية، أوه، هناك حفرة.
And you will fall, and you will die. Dangerous.
سوف تسقط، وتموت. خطير.
That's why, perhaps, you will try to have this angle of vision.
لهذا السبب ربما، سوف تحاول الحصول على هذه الزاوية من الرؤية.
OK, I can see, if I found something, up, up, and they continue, up up up.
حسنا ، أستطيع أن أرى، إذا وجدت شيئا، هب، هب ، ثم أستمر، هب هب هب.
I raise the angle of vision, but it's still very -- selfish, selfish, egoiste -- yes, selfish.
سوف أرفع زاوية الرؤيا، ولكنها لا تزال في غاية -- الأنانية، أنانية --- نعم، أنانية.
You, you survive. It's OK.
تستطيع البقاء على قيد الحياة. لا بأس.
If you raise the level of your eyes a little more you go,
إذا رفعت مستوى عينيك إكثر من ذلك،
"I see you, oh my God you are here, how are you, I can help you,
أستطيع رؤيتكم، يا إلهي أنت هنا، كيف حالك، أستطيع مساعدتك.
I can design for you a new toothbrush, new toilet brush," something like that.
أستطيع تصميم فرشاة أسنان جديدة لك، فرشاة مرحاض جديدة." شئ من هذا القبيل.
I live in society; I live in community.
أنا أعيش في المجتمع.
It's OK. You start to be in the territory of intelligence, we can say.
لا بأس. يمكننا قول أنك بدأت تصبح في منطقة الذكاء.
From this level, the more you can raise this angle of view,
من هذا المنطق، كلما أمكنك زيادة مستوى زاوية الرؤية،
the more you will be important for the society.
كلما أصبحت أكثر أهمية للمجتمع.
The more you will rise, the more you will be important for the civilization.
وكلما ارتفعت، سوف تكون أكثر أهمية للحضارة.
The more you will rise, to see far and high, like that,
وكلما ارتفت، لرؤية بعيدة وعالية، وهكذا،
the more you will be important for the story of our mutation.
كلما أصبحت أكثر أهمية لقصة تحولنا.
That means intelligent people are in this angle. That is intelligence.
هذا يعني أن الناس الأذكياء في هذه الزاوية. هذا هو الذكاء.
From this to here, that, it's genius.
من هذا إلى هنا، إنها عبقرية.
Ptolemy, Eratosthenes, Einstein, things like that.
بطليموس، إراتوستينس، آينشتاين، وأشياء من هذا القبيل.
Nobody's obliged to be a genius.
لا أحد ملزم أن يكون عبقريا.
It's better, but nobody.
بالتأكيد إنه أفضل، لكن لا أحد ملزم.
Take care, in this training, to be a good mutant.
خذ الحيطة والحذر في هذا التدريب، لتكون متحول جيد.
There is some danger, there is some trap. One trap: the vertical.
هناك بعض الخطر، وهناك بعض الأفخاخ. فخ واحد : العمودي.
Because at the vertical of us, if you look like that,
لأن في المستوى الرأسي لكل واحد منا، اذا نظرتم من هذا القبيل،
"Ah! my God, there is God. Ah! God!"
"آه! يإلهي، هناك رب. آه! يا رب!"
God is a trap. God is the answer when we don't know the answer.
الرب هو فخ. الرب هو الجواب عندما لا نعرف الجواب.
That means, when your brain is not enough big, when you don't understand,
هذا يعني، عندما لا يكون عقلك كبير بما فيه الكفاية، عندما لا تفهم،
you go, "Ah, it's God, it's God." That's ridiculous.
وتستمر، "آه، لأنه الرب، والرب موجود." هذا امر سخيف.
That's why -- jump, like that? No, don't jump.
لهذا السبب -- القفز، هكذا؟ لا، لا تقفز.
Come back. Because, after, there is another trap.
إرجع. لأنه، بعد ذلك، هناك فخ آخر.
If you look like that, you look to the past,
إذا كنت تبدو مثل ذلك، فأنت تنظر إلى الماضي،
or you look inside if you are very flexible, inside yourself.
أو تبحث في داخل نفسك إذا كنت مرن، داخل نفسك.
It's called schizophrenia, and you are dead also.
هذا يدعى إنفصام في الشخصية، وأنت ميت أيضا.
That's why every morning, now, because you are a good mutant,
هذا هو السبب أنك في كل صباح، والآن، لأنك متحول جيد،
you will raise your angle of view.
سوف ترفع زاوية رؤيتك.
Out, more of the horizontal. You are an intelligence.
من الخارج، أكثر في الأفقية. أنت في غاية الذكاء.
Never forget -- like that, like that.
لا تنسى أبدا -- وهكذا.
It's very, very, very important.
إنه في غاية الأهمية.
What, what else we can say about that? Why do that?
ماذا يمكننا أيضا أن نقول عن ذلك. لماذا نفعل ذلك؟
It's because we -- if we look from far, we see our line of evolution.
ذلك لأننا -- إذا نظرنا من بعيد، سوف نرى خط التطور.
This line of evolution is clearly positive.
هذا الخط من التطور واضح إيجابيا.
From far, this line looks very smooth, like that.
من بعيد، هذا الخط يبدو على نحو سلس جدا، هكذا.
But if you take a lens, like that, this line is ack, ack, ack, ack, ack. Like that.
ولكن إذا أخذنا عدسة، هذا الخط سيكون متعرج. هكذا.
It's made of light and shadow.
إنه مصنوع من الضوء والظل.
We can say light is civilization, shadow is barbaria.
يمكننا القول أن الضوء يمثل الحضارة، والظل يمثل الهمجية.
And it's very important to know where we are.
ومن المهم جدا أن نعرف أين نحن.
Because some cycle, there is a spot in the cycle,
لأنه في بعض الدورات، هناك بقعة في الدورة،
and you have not the same duty in the different parts of the cycle.
وليس لديك الواجب نفسه في أجزاء مختلفة من الدورة.
That means, we can imagine -- I don't say it was fantastic,
وهذا يعني ، يمكننا أن نتصور -- لا أقول أنها كانت رائعة،
but in the '80s, there was not too much war, like that, it was --
ولكن في الثمانينات، لم يكن هناك الكثير من الحروب، هكذا، كانت --
we can imagine that the civilization can become civilized.
يمكننا أن نتصور أن الحضارة يمكن أن تصبح متحضرة.
In this case, people like me are acceptable.
في هذه الحالة ، الناس مثلي يكونوا مقبولين.
We can say, "It's luxurious time."
يمكننا القول، "إنه وقت الفخامة."
We have time to think, we have time to I don't know what,
لدينا الوقت للتفكير، لدينا الوقت لأمور مثل،
speak about art and things like that.
التحدث عن الفن وأمور من هذا القبيل.
It's OK. We are in the light.
لا بأس. نحن في الضوء.
But sometimes, like today, we fall, we fall so fast, so fast to shadow, we fall so fast to barbaria.
لكن في بعض الأحيان، مثل اليوم، سوف نقع، نقع بسرعة، إلى الظل، نقع بسرعة إلى الهمجية.
With many, many, many, many face of barbaria.
مع العديد والعديد من أوجه الهمجية.
Because it's not, the barbaria we have today, it's perhaps not the barbaria we think.
لأنها ليست الهمجية التي لدينا اليوم، انها ربما ليست الهمجية التي نعتقدها.
There is different type of barbaria.
هناك أنواع مختلفة من الهمجية.
That's why we must adapt.
ولهذا السبب لا بد أن نتأقلم.
That means, when barbaria is back, forget the beautiful chairs, forget the beautiful hotel,
هذا يعني، عندما تعود الهمجية، انسى الكراسي الجميلة، وانسى الفندق الجميل،
forget design, even -- I'm sorry to say -- forget art.
انسى التصميم، وحتى -- أنا آسف أن أقول -- انسى الفن.
Forget all that. There is priority; there is urgency.
انسى كل ذلك. هناك أولوية، وهناك أمور ملحة.
You must go back to politics, you must go back to radicalization,
يجب أن تعود إلى السياسة، ويجب أن تعود إلى التطرف،
I'm sorry if that's not very English.
أنا آسف اذا لم يكن هذا باللغة الانجليزية.
You must go back to fight, to battle.
يجب أن تعود إلى القتال، إلى المعركة.
That's why today I'm so ashamed to make this job.
لهذا السبب أنا أخجل اليوم أن أعمل هذا العمل.
That's why I am here, to try to do it the best possible.
لهذا السبب أنا هنا، في محاولة للقيام بذلك على أفضل وجه ممكن.
But I know that even I do it the best possible
لكني أعلم أنه حتى إذا قمت بعمل ذلك على أفضل وجه ممكن
-- that's why I'm the best -- it's nothing.
-- لهذا السبب أنا الأفضل -- إنه لا شيء.
Because it's not the right time.
لأنه ليس الوقت المناسب.
That's why I say that. I say that, because, I repeat, nothing exist if it's not in the good rhythym,
لهذا السبب أنا أقول ذلك. أقول ذلك ، لأنه، وأكرر، لا شيء موجود إذا لم يكن لسبب وجيه،
the rhythym of our beautiful dream, of this civilization.
سبب حلمنا الجميل، لهذه الحضارة.
And because we must all work to finish this story.
ولأن علينا جميعا أن نعمل لإنهاء هذه القصة.
Because the scenario of this civilization
لأن سيناريو هذه الحضارة
-- about love, progress, and things like that -- it's OK,
-- عن الحب، والتقدم، وأشياء من هذا القبيل -- لا بأس،
but there is so many different, other scenarios of other civilizations.
ولكن هناك أمور أخرى مختلفة كثيرا، سيناريوهات أخرى لحضارات أخرى.
This scenario, of this civilization, was about becoming powerful, intelligent,
سيناريو هذه الحضارة، كان حول الوصول إلى القوة والذكاء،
like this idea we have invented, this concept of God.
من هذه الفكرة لقد اخترعنا، هذا المفهوم للرب.
We are God now. We are. It's almost done.
نحن أصبحنا الرب الان. انها على وشك الإنتهاء.
We have just to finish the story.
بقي لدينا إنهاء القصة فقط.
That is very, very important.
إنه في غاية الأهمية.
And when you don't understand really what's happened,
وعندما لا تفهم حقا ما الذي يحدث،
you cannot go and fight and work and build and things like that.
لا يمكنك الذهاب والكفاح والعمل والبناء، واشياء من هذا القبيل.
You go to the future back, back, back, back, like that.
تذهب إلى المستقبل، إلى الوراء، إلى الوراء، إلى الوراء، هكذا.
And you can fall, and it's very dangerous.
وقد تسقط، وهذا امر خطير جدا.
No, you must really understand that.
لا، يجب أن نفهم حقا.
Because we have almost finished, I'll repeat this story.
لأنننا على وشك الانتهاء تقريبا، سوف أكرر هذه القصة.
And the beauty of this, in perhaps 50 years, 60 years, we can finish completely this civilization,
والجميل في هذا، ربما في 50 سنة، 60 سنة، يمكن أن ننهي هذه الحضارة تماما،
and offer to our children the possibility to invent a new story,
ونقدم لأطفالنا إمكانية ابتكار قصة جديدة،
a new poetry, a new romanticism.
عاطفة جديدة، رومانسية جديدة.
With billions of people who have been born, worked, lived and died before us,
مع البلايين من البشر الذين ولدوا، وعملوا، وعاشوا وماتوا من قبلنا،
these people who have worked so much,
هؤلاء الناس الذين عملوا كثيرا،
we have now bring beautiful things, beautiful gifts, we know so many things.
لقد قمنا بتحقيق أشياء جميلة، وهدايا جميلة، نحن نعرف الكثير من الأشياء.
We can say to our children, OK, done, that was our story. That passed.
يمكننا أن نقول لأطفالنا، حسنا،، هذه كانت قصتنا. التي انقضت.
Now you have a duty: invent a new story. Invent a new poetry.
الآن لديكم واجب: اخترعوا قصة جديدة. اخترعوا أدب جديد.
The only rule is, we have not to have any idea about the next story.
والقاعدة الوحيدة هي، ليس لديهم أي فكرة عن القصة المقبلة.
We give you white pages. Invent.
قدمنا لكم صفحات بيضاء. اخترعوا.
We give you the best tools, the best tools, and now, do it.
قدمنا لكم أفضل الأدوات، والآن، حان الوقت لتفعلوا ذلك.
That's why I continue to work, even if it's for toilet brush.
لهذا السبب ما زلت أعمل، حتى لو كان لصنع فرشاة المرحاض.